Typhoon 13 is continuing to the north with extraordinary force.
Minami Daitou entered the storm's area of effect at around 11PM last night.
Its effect on transport systems in various areas is currently...
Daikichi!
TL Note: "Unko" in Japanese is "poo". "Unkou" means "running".
The TV says the bullet trains are doing a poo!
Not "doing a poo"! "Running"!
Poo?
Running!
I bet they said that normal bullet train service is "running", right?
That just means they're working like they normally do.
Woo, woo! The trains are doing a poo!
I'm going to go and do a poo!
Jeez...
It is predicted that Typhoon 13 will
gradually shift its course towards the east...
...and land in the Tokai area as evening turns into night.
They said a typhoon!
It's fine. They come around every year.
Daikichi!
No toilet paper left?
I did a really amazing one!
Bring a ruler!
They do say boys don't mature as fast as girls, but...
She must really have it hard.
Usagi
Drop
I can't tell what'll come tomorrow.
ashita no koto wa wakaranai
明日のことはわからない
This is different than making a sacrifice.
kore tte gisei to wa chigau
これって犠牲とは違う
Something about it is different.
nanika ga chigau
何かが違う
And I don't think of it as some sort of forfeit.
batsu geemu ja nante omowanai
罰ゲームじゃなんて思わない
So I just don't get why.
...tte nande na no ka wakaranai
...ってなんでなのか分からない
I can't quite wrap my head around it,
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
ちょっと釈然としないけど
but your existence is now much more than just important to me.
kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nante mon ja nai
君の存在今大事だなんてもんじゃない
There's nothing in this world that doesn't come to an end.
owaranai koto nante kono yo no doko ni mo nai
終わらないことなんてこの世のどこにもない
I don't cry because I'm hurting.
naku no wa tsurain ja nai no
泣くのは辛いんじゃないの
They're the sweet, sweet drops of love!
ai no sweet drops sweet drops
愛の sweet drops sweet drops
I want to go on dreaming forever, you know?
zutto yume mite mitai ne
ずっと夢見てみたいね
I want to try and be more gentle, you know?
motto yasashiku shitai ne
もっと優しくしたいね
If I can be with you, I'm happy.
kimi to iraretara happy
君といられたらhappy
Girls are really strong, aren't they?
onna no ko tte tsuyoi ne
女の子って強いね
But sometimes, they can be really weak, you know?
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne
だけど時々弱いね
Our wishes are happy, happy, happy.
bokura no negai wa happy happy happy
僕らの願いは happy happy happy
And our days will be just as happy!
sonna hibi mo happy
そんな日々も happy
Just wanna make you happy!
I'll pick you up early today, okay?
Yeah.
Let's go, Kouki-kun.
Isn't that awesome?
We're going to be late!
See you!
If you leave just the right amount of space where I drew the circles, it'll look nice.
Understand?
Sensei, how much is "just the right amount"?
Um...
How many centimetres? How many millimetres?
You don't have to draw these circles!
Okay!
We'll leave the rest for homework.
For your next class, everyone in the first year will be drawing together.
Gather outside beside your own morning glory.
Understood?
Yes!
Are sandbags really that heavy?
It's not even the afternoon, and I'm already burned out.
Just our luck that we have a bunch of
samples to ship out on top of everything.
Thanks.
What's that?
My kids' educational insurance.
What?! But they're still babies, right?
It wouldn't be worth it to get insurance if I waited until they were older.
I-I guess so...
I paid for mine, too, just in case.
Though I doubt my kid will make it to university.
We've got two kids, so it's tough going.
Ours is still so young that we've
got to worry about daycare fees, too.
Outgrows his clothes right away, too.
Though, we're lucky enough to get pensions and health insurance, even though we're not with a company.
What about life insurance?
My wife took care of that before I knew it.
Mine pays a lump sum if I die, and hers is tied to her savings account.
Pretty basic stuff.
You guys really are dads, aren't you?
It's pretty amazing.
Not at all.
I wonder how much insurance costs.
The kid next door is so loud that we want to move,
but we don't have the money.
Yeah. Kind of makes you wonder what you're working for, huh?
You should take a good look at us, too.
This is what happens when you get married.
I don't have a girlfriend, anyway, so I'm fine.
They say that, but no matter how much they complain...
...you can tell they're perfectly content.
I can't imagine any of them ever becoming like Rin's mother.
Kouki-san!
Sit down and draw like you're supposed to!
Crap!
What about your drawing board?
The ground is flat, so I don't really need it.
That's not acceptable!
When you're told to bring something, you bring it!
Right now! Run!
Wow, your picture's really good, Rin-chan!
You're right, it's amazing! So pretty!
Really?
It really is good!
The colours of these two flowers are slightly different,
and that's reflected in Rin-san's drawing, with a purple flower and a blue one.
That was observant of you.
Kouki-kun and the others are messing around again.
Kouki-san...
It's drawing time right now.
Your morning glories are amazing, Kouki-san.
It'd be a waste not to sketch them.
Do you like drawing?
I don't mind it, I guess.
Tatsumi-sensei, I'm his teacher.
Kouki-san, why do you always do your best to disturb everyone?
Sit down and start drawing already.
And no funny faces.
I have Kouki's hat!
Stop it!
Hey! Kouki-san! You boys! Stop messing around!
Get back here at once!
Got it! Got it!
Rin-chan?
Kouki-kun!
Sit down and draw properly!
Don't let them distract you!
Okay.
That was amazing, Rin-chan.
Kouki-kun's always acting up, and he's scary when he gets mad.
He'll bully you!
He will not!
We were at nursery together.
Really?
They're late.
You guys have to meet your kids at six, too, right?
Yeah. We're cutting it close today.
They're here!
Right, let's get this done and dusted!
Yeah!
Hello!
Ah, looks like you got soaked.
Rin-chan! Your father's here!
Hey!
I-I'm sorry.
Don't worry about it at all.
I'll go and get Rin-chan.
The wind's gotten stronger, huh?
Yeah. I wanted to get here earlier.
Am I the last to pick up?
Just you and Kouki-kun.
Daikichi!
There's a storm, huh?
Yeah. It's pretty wild outside.
Sorry I'm late.
It's fine.
An umbrella's flying!
Did something happen?
No, it's fine.
See you!
See you later, Kouki!
Let's go home together.
Would you like to go home together?
Sure!
I'm sorry, but there's really no way that we can...
I know. But the wind's only going to get more and more fierce, so can...
I call Nitani-san and see if it's okay,
and then pass her over to you for confirmation?
Well, if you put it like that...
That means we'll be going home early, too!
What's that supposed to mean?!
Just a little joke.
Kouki!
Me, too!
R-Rin!
That's dangerous. Get behind me and follow closely.
Hold it right there!
I'll go and get you towels.
Ah, the storm shutters!
Cool! Let me try!
Here you go. Don't get your fingers caught.
It's dark.
It's sort of like a secret base, huh?
It's in my eyes!
I'll rinse it out. Keep your eyes shut.
Right. Dry the rest yourself.
Daikichi, your back is huge!
I know, right?
Good evening! It's Nitani!
Right! Coming!
Daikichi makes really
good beef and
potatoes. And he
can run fast.
My guardian
Daikichi
So they let you out of work early?
I felt like I was sticking my nose in where I shouldn't have.
Not at all! You've been such a big help!
Sorry, Kouki got soaked, too.
I really don't know how to begin to thank you.
That suits you!
Lend me yours, Daikichi!
I've told you to call him "Daikichi-san"!
He said "Daikichi" is fine!
I'm more comfortable with that, too.
That's right!
It's best for Daikichi to just be Daikichi!
You're really good at that, Rin-chan!
I can use a knife, too!
You're already a big girl, aren't you?
Daikichi works with the flame, though.
I'll do it, too!
But you never help out...
I'll cut, too!
I'll lend you my knife!
Oh, no! Onions are the worst!
Don't touch! Go and rinse your eyes!
Where are you going!
Oh, no, I'm crying!
These are supposed to be... hamburgers?
Yeah. Looks good, huh?
They're kind of weird.
They are not! Right?
I'm sure they'll taste fine.
Rin-chan! The eggs are hard boiled!
Can you peel them for me?
Okay!
Here!
You're really good at that!
That Rin... She's getting so excited.
Kouki, do you love your mum?
Well... She's kind of an old nag, but...
There's a definite feeling of content here, too.
This one is mine!
You didn't even say "let's eat".
Let's eat!
Kouki, use your chopsticks.
I know. I'm just gathering it together.
It's good, isn't it?
It really is!
Food always tastes better when everyone eats together.
Let's eat here again tomorrow!
K-Kouki!
You can leave the dishes there.
I'll do them later.
Okay...
And then, it hit him on the head!
They're so excited...
I haven't been able to give Kouki many opportunities like this until now, so...
I'm really glad we had this evening.
Thank you!
Not at all! We should be thanking you.
Sensei said we didn't need those circles!
Being able to seem him smile like that...
I'm so glad I got off work early.
She's raising a child on her own, just like me...
Daikichi! Come here a second!
Coming...
We'd better be off, then.
Shall I call a taxi?
Yes, thank you!
Why don't you stay over?
Rin!
But Reina-chan and her mum stayed over...
That was different.
See you later.
Later.
Bye-bye!
Rin-chan, thank you.
Thank you so much.
We had fun, as well.
Right?
Yeah!
Bye-bye!
A sunny Sunday's early afternoon;
nichiyou no hareta hirusagari
日曜の晴れた昼下がり
where should we go today?
kyou wa doko e yukou?
今日はどこへ行こう？
The same old road that I'm so used to walking on...
kayoinareta itsumo no michi ga
通い慣れたいつもの道が
...shines with a dazzling light.
mabushiku kagayaite mieru
眩しく 輝いて見える
If I have the warm sunlight shining down on me...
terasu atatakai taiyou to
照らす暖かい太陽と
...and you by my side...
tonari ni kimi ga ireba...
隣に君がいれば
Whoa! High, high, high!
My feelings are ready to burst forth.
hashagidasu kimochi ni
はしゃぎだす気持ちに
Sing out, lai lai lai!
utae lai lai lai!
歌え lai lai lai!
My voice reaches every corner of the earth.
koe wa doko made mo
声はどこまでも
I'm already high, high, high!
mou high high high!
もう high high high!
Riding the whirling winds...
maiagaru kaze ni nori
舞い上がる風に乗り
Sing out, lai lai lai!
utae lai lai lai!
歌え lai lai lai!
My voice swoops up and down with me.
koe mo tobihaneru
声も飛び跳ねる
The typhoon's gone, huh?
Looks like it.
Rin-chan! Rin-chan!
Kouki-kun's here already!
He's early again!
Come in!
Is it okay?
Wait!
I wanted to open the storm shutters...
The sky's as clear as can be!
See you later!
Kouki-kun, we're going to be late!
Later!